<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://randommusings.netlify.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://randommusings.netlify.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-10T18:00:47+05:30</updated><id>https://randommusings.netlify.com/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Random Musings</title><subtitle>A geek's eclectic contemplations</subtitle><author><name>Divay Prakash</name><email>divayprakash0@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Small updates</title><link href="https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/2020/03/09/small-updates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Small updates" /><published>2020-03-09T17:31:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-03-09T17:31:00+05:30</updated><id>https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/2020/03/09/small-updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/2020/03/09/small-updates.html">&lt;p&gt;How does it happen that simple things always manage to take up so much time? I don’t have the first clue, but I know it’s true. It’s happened to me too much for me to not believe in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, I’ve been working on a few things for the blog. Started working yesterday evening around 6PM and making some small changes -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Darkened the background color - it’s now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.colorhexa.com/111111&quot;&gt;#111111&lt;/a&gt; instead of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.colorhexa.com/15171d&quot;&gt;#15171d&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made an effort to speed up the deployment process by having the script create a shallow clone of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;random-musings-deploy&lt;/code&gt; repo. Doesn’t really seem to be making much of a difference for now, but I’ll look into this later.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed masthead from all pages except the index page - This one has really been bugging me for a long time. I just could not for the life of me figure out why it made sense to have the masthead on all the pages. So I removed it! This also allowed me to simplify the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;masthead.md&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_includes&lt;/code&gt; file a bunch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customized masthead - I didn’t like that the blog title was smaller than the post titles below it. Fixed that and also used a custom font.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Colourize output of deploy script - Just did this for fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;align-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cool.gif&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Cool, right?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Divay Prakash</name><email>divayprakash0@gmail.com</email></author><category term="enhancement" /><summary type="html">How does it happen that simple things always manage to take up so much time? I don’t have the first clue, but I know it’s true. It’s happened to me too much for me to not believe in it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Promises Promises</title><link href="https://randommusings.netlify.com/life/2020/03/06/promises-promises.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Promises Promises" /><published>2020-03-06T23:23:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-03-06T23:23:00+05:30</updated><id>https://randommusings.netlify.com/life/2020/03/06/promises-promises</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://randommusings.netlify.com/life/2020/03/06/promises-promises.html">&lt;p&gt;I made a promise to myself to stop wasting time watching random shit on Youtube and instead use that time to read something or blog or just do anything else more productive. A progress report - I’m doing better… &lt;em&gt;sort of&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why only “sort of”? Well, I haven’t done as much of the other stuff as I wanted to. THe past few days got surprisingly busy with something or the other coming up just randomly all over the place. I met an old colleague on the 2nd so there went a day. The 3rd saw me preparing for a stupid viva for school and then 4th went into the stupid viva itself and studying (well, teaching rather) for a test on the 5th. Of course, 5th then went into the test itself and the rest of the day spent in playing pool and going out for drinks with a friend who’d fallen by the wayside (nope, that’s not correct, make it - “a friend who’d forgotten me by the wayside”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that brings me on to ‘promises promises.’ It just happens so often doesn’t it? We promise ourselves or someone else something or the other, and then somehow it just does not work out that way. Why is it? Why are we as humans so unable to keep our promises that we disappoint ourselves or someone close to us so often? I don’t know the answer to that one either, but I have a theory. It goes like this - humans are inherently deceptive. We deceive ourselves and others around us all the time! According to my theory, it’s all down to two factors -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Conscious conditioning - Consider as an example any primary school event. Everyone is a winner. There are no prizes for coming first or putting in any special effort. Why? It’s done in the name of not discouraging any single child. However, children are not stupid. THey know winners from losers. And whatever else this policy does or doesn’t, it shows children the willingness of the adults around them to deceive, to lie. This isn’t just restricted to school, you can see it pretty much anywhere&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hope -&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Hope, it is the quintessential human delusion, simultaneously the source of your greatest strength, and your greatest weakness.&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scottmanning.com/content/the-architect-transcript/&quot;&gt;The Architect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0234215/&quot;&gt;The Matrix Reloaded&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I do believe this applies here. Hope is something we humans always seem to have just a little more of. However dire the situation may be, we still hope. We even have a phrase for it - “hope against all hope”! This drives us to say things we are not sure of and make promises we know we may not be able to keep.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The culmination of all this results in the lies we utter everyday and the promises we make knowing full well we won’t be able to keep them. My friend promised me to always have space for me in her life, and of course she couldn’t keep it. I promised myself not to feel bad about it when it (eventually) fell through but I did. And so on it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What to do about this? Fair question, but there is no real answer. Well, there is, but it requires a lot of effort - introspection. Thinking about what we say before we say it. Understanding the meaning in our own words, whether they be addressed to ourselves or to someone else. This is paramount. Only then can we begin to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I don’t really have a simple conclusion here. Philosophy gives me a headache sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Divay Prakash</name><email>divayprakash0@gmail.com</email></author><category term="philosophy" /><summary type="html">I made a promise to myself to stop wasting time watching random shit on Youtube and instead use that time to read something or blog or just do anything else more productive. A progress report - I’m doing better… sort of.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">So much to do… and SO MUCH time to do it in</title><link href="https://randommusings.netlify.com/life/2020/02/26/so-much-to-do-and-so-much-time-to-do-it-in.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So much to do... and SO MUCH time to do it in" /><published>2020-02-26T14:10:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-02-26T14:10:00+05:30</updated><id>https://randommusings.netlify.com/life/2020/02/26/so-much-to-do-and-so-much-time-to-do-it-in</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://randommusings.netlify.com/life/2020/02/26/so-much-to-do-and-so-much-time-to-do-it-in.html">&lt;p&gt;In the words of the hallowed ‘Satchmo’ -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;There’s so little time and so much to do&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://genius.com/Louis-armstrong-so-little-time-so-much-to-do-lyrics&quot;&gt;Louis “Satchmo” Armstrong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, I am in my last semester of MBA studies at SCMHRD. Classes are over, and it’s only a few sporadic tests or assignment submissions here and there to occupy my time. I got a PPO (pre-placement offer) from a great organisation, so I am totally ready-to-go in that respect. This means that most of my time, and I mean entire days on end are completely free. Which should be such a great thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except that it’s not. It is really really not. I often find myself procrastinating. And even more often, just simply wasting time. It depends on the kind of mindset I am in at the moment. I spend hours on end watching YouTube videos. It’s true that I stay away from inane garbage, but even just sticking to technology/automotive videos and educational content leaves me open to a vast library. I believe it enhances my knowledge, and I have often found myself able to better explain myself, or join a conversation, or help someone, just because I watched some video which gave me some tiny bit of information. But is it really productive in the larger scheme of things? This is what I meant when I said it depends on my mindset at a given moment, how I view this time spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might seem really picayune to some, but to me it is really not. Increasingly, I find myself trying to tear my attention away from the video I am watching, or trying to prevent my fingers from typing out ‘youtube’ in the browser’s address bar. I’ve gotten so used to it that whenever I open up my laptop, I somehow automatically end up staring at the YouTube homepage!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to sum it all up, I’ve concluded that it is not the best use of my time just ‘watching’ endlessly, not ‘doing’ anything of my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this also led me on to a bigger realisation. And it’s not the first time I’ve had this realisation, it ‘comes and goes’, as they say. Anyway, the realisation is this - the human mind is made to be occupied. It is meant to be working on something. Taking a break, relaxing, travelling, all that is okay, but in the end, if our brains are twiddling their thumbs on a regular, everyday basis, then that just doesn’t work. It becomes difficult to apply oneself after such a hiatus from any constructive thought. And it’s also true that while time is spend on thinking nothing, you are equally prone to negative thought. I am currently in the middle of a massive family issue concerning myself very deeply and I often find myself falling into this destructive pattern where I keep thinking of it, even when I know there is nothing but time that will solve the issue and my thinking about it is not going to accomplish anything!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Satchmo says, it is often in life that we find ourselves wishing we had more time. I can attest to that because that has been the state of affairs for me for the past 24 years of my life. And it hurts knowing we could have accomplished more if only our day was an hour longer. But, on the other hand, it is equally hard to sit around doing nothing. In my opinion, it is even worse!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set a goal for myself today - to spend time doing anything other than consuming content. The world we live in today gives us so many avenues to just consume content rather than doing something of our own. But I need to make a conscious effort to not give in to the urge of doing the easy thing - watching videos. Truthfully speaking, there is so much more I could be doing. Maybe an online course to enhance my knowledge and skills. Maybe being more regular with this blog. Maybe pursuing one of my other interests - art, music, gaming, anything! And maybe even taking that solo trip that I’ve been longing to do for years now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a gift - to have time to devote to whatever you want. I plan to start using the gift that I’ve been given, starting now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Divay Prakash</name><email>divayprakash0@gmail.com</email></author><category term="boredom" /><category term="time" /><category term="philosophy" /><summary type="html">In the words of the hallowed ‘Satchmo’ -</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">It’s done!</title><link href="https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/21/it-s-done.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It's done!" /><published>2020-02-21T12:32:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-02-21T12:32:00+05:30</updated><id>https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/21/it-s-done</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/21/it-s-done.html">&lt;p&gt;After various false starts over the past years and days of trial and error (and the associated misery and joy) in this instance, I’m finally at a place where I can say that -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The blog is done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very least, it’s done enough that I don’t feel the need to tinker with it any more&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to change this or that and I’m comfortable just getting on with the business of actually putting my thoughts and feelings down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;align-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/happy.gif&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Because I'm happy... :notes:&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how did I get here? Well, as I talked about in my &lt;a href=&quot;/blogging/code/2020/02/19/success.html&quot;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, deployment with Netlify worked like a breeze. However, I wanted to shorten the build times just to simplify things on the server end and make everything less of a pain to setup again if need be. The setup I currently have makes this virtually painless! Here’s how it works -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The main Jekyll blog files are present in a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/divayprakash/random-musings/&quot;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;. I clone this on my local machine and run a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt; and it’s ready to go&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can create posts, add asset files, and whatever I need to do - here, in this repo. All this is saved with a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git commit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a separate &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/divayprakash/random-musings-deploy/&quot;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once I’m done working, I simply run the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deploy.sh&lt;/code&gt; script which does all the heavy lifting for deployment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/divayprakash/random-musings/blob/master/deploy.sh&quot;&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; runs through the following steps -
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Push &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; repo&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Delete old &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder and create anew&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clone the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt; repo into new &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Read details of last commit in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; repo on local machine&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Build Jekyll site&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Switch to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add site files generated in step 5 in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder to index of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt; repo&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Creates commit in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt; repo with commit message using details extracted in step 4&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Push commits to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt; repo&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Delete &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;As a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;bonus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Print updates, divided into 3 categories - ‘STATUS’, ‘SUCCESS’, ‘FAILURE’&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Exit gracefully in case any command fails, along with an appropriate error message&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Netlify deploy is triggered whenever the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt; repo is updated, copying the static website files generated by Jekyll over to Netlify’s servers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New and updated site goes live &lt;a href=&quot;https://randommusings.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script does all this work so I don’t have to. I know it’s very rudimentary, but it’s basic automation at its best. I’m really pleased with the results; the deploy time on Netlify has been cut down from over 5 minutes to just &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;6 seconds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;align-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/up-to-eleven.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Automation &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Up_to_eleven&quot;&gt;up to 11!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Very much an &lt;em&gt;only at the moment&lt;/em&gt; feeling, if I’m being perfectly honest. I am a perfectionist at heart so no project of mine is ever truly finished. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Divay Prakash</name><email>divayprakash0@gmail.com</email></author><category term="misadventure" /><category term="success" /><summary type="html">After various false starts over the past years and days of trial and error (and the associated misery and joy) in this instance, I’m finally at a place where I can say that -</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Success*</title><link href="https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/19/success.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Success*" /><published>2020-02-19T18:30:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-02-19T18:30:00+05:30</updated><id>https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/19/success</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/19/success.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When life gives you lemons, chunk it right back.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/112530-when-life-gives-you-lemons-chunk-it-right-back&quot;&gt;Bill Waterson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess life is handing out lemons today. Oh how I’d like to chunk them right back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Netlify works! It just works. It’s simple to set up and painless to maintain. All I had to do was revert to the gem based theme and then follow the basic setup process for deployment of the blog repository on Netlify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, at this point, I should be happy… right? after all, I did get a working solution. However, for the basic free tier, Netlify allows a maximum of 300 build minutes/month. And guess what, each build of my blog takes &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;over 5 mins&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;! That’s with no extra features, nothing outside of a simple Jekyll deployment. At that rate, I have around 60 builds a month before I exceed my plan limits. I don’t think I would ever be exceeding that, but it’s nice to live with abandon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This led me to think of employing a post commit hook. What I’d like to achieve is this -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write a post, make some change to the blog, whatever&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Commit change to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Post-commit hook builds the site, copies &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; over to a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt; branch (could also be done using a dedicated script)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Both &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt; branches are pushed to Github&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Netlify watches the repo for pushes to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt; branch (instead of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; like it currently does). Commits here are then used to trigger a deploy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, the entire process of building the site takes places on my local machine, where it takes &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;~2 seconds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s a massive difference!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so it goes on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Divay Prakash</name><email>divayprakash0@gmail.com</email></author><category term="life" /><category term="lemons" /><summary type="html">I guess life is handing out lemons today. Oh how I'd like to chunk them right back.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ray of Hope</title><link href="https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/19/ray-of-hope.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ray of Hope" /><published>2020-02-19T11:32:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-02-19T11:32:00+05:30</updated><id>https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/19/ray-of-hope</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/19/ray-of-hope.html">&lt;figure class=&quot;align-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/rey-of-hope.gif&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;'Rey' of hope!... No?... Ok, I'll show myself out...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, a possibility of light at the end of the tunnel. Considering the pit of despair I am in at the moment, a shred of hope is better than nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browsing through some random forum&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; gave me a possible solution - Netlify. Just as a thought exercise (and even though I am desperately trying not to get my hopes up too much), this seems quite plausible. Github isn’t a hosting provider, Netlify is. So it makes sense that it supports a larger number of build pipelines and doesn’t bind you to the same constraints as Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To top it all off, Netlify even has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/blog/2017/05/11/migrating-your-jekyll-site-to-netlify/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; up on their blog with instructions on how to migrate a Jekyll site to their platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fingers crossed this works! :crossed_fingers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;maybe it was StackOverflow, or Jekyll forums, or a Github issue/PR, I don’t even know at this point! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Divay Prakash</name><email>divayprakash0@gmail.com</email></author><category term="hope" /><category term="solution" /><summary type="html">Finally, a possibility of light at the end of the tunnel. Considering the pit of despair I am in at the moment, a shred of hope is better than nothing at all.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Misery</title><link href="https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/19/misery.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Misery" /><published>2020-02-19T01:23:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-02-19T01:23:00+05:30</updated><id>https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/19/misery</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/19/misery.html">&lt;p&gt;At the point I &lt;a href=&quot;/blogging/code/2020/02/16/blogging-like-a-hacker.html&quot;&gt;last posted&lt;/a&gt;, I was just getting into exploring a new Jekyll theme for my blog. Now, after having sunk just over 3 days into the endeavour I find myself here, in abject misery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overview of the past few hours -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It started simply enough, implementing a new theme. I remember saying to myself -
    &lt;figure class=&quot;align-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/how-hard-can-it-be.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Oh, how I'd regret that...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And initially, it really wasn’t. I had struggled through Jekyll, Liquid, and Textile long enough to know how to adapt the theme to my uses and add my own content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I had chosen to use the Ruby Gem based method of installing the theme; ‘cause I thought having the theme gem installed would ease the process of development on my local machine which, as it turned out, was a correct assumption. So far this was what I had -&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Gemfile&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;jekyll-theme-so-simple&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-yaml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# _config.yml&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;theme&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;jekyll-theme-so-simple&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This worked perfectly, but as I was soon to find out, it only worked on my local machine. Github Pages does not support gem-based themes as it does not read Gemfiles at all! So when I pushed my work to a new repo, this was what I ended up with -&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-console highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;Your SCSS file `assets/css/main.scss` has an error on line 13: File to import
not found or unreadable: so-simple. For more information, see
https://help.github.com/en/github/working-with-github-pages/
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;troubleshooting-jekyll-build-errors-for-github-pages-sites#&lt;/span&gt;invalid-sass-or-scss
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;figure class=&quot;align-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/are-you-kidding-me.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Back to square 1 then. Digging into the details, I found that the only way to make sure I could have seamless theme updates (which I really wanted), was to use the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;remote_theme&lt;/code&gt; method which GitHub supported, now that the Gem based themed method had failed. And so the next commits removed the code above and added this -&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Gemfile&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;github-pages&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;group: :jekyll_plugins&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;group&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:jekyll_plugins&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;jekyll-remote-theme&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-yaml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# _config.yml&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;remote_theme&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;mmistakes/so-simple-theme@3.2.0&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Just as an aside, I think the commit messages are worth a mention -&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-console highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;commit 363cc6961d2921ac1866b9e21c14450581e73b22
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;Author: Divay Prakash &amp;lt;divayprakash0@gmail.com&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;Date:   Tue Feb 18 00:21:15 2020 +0530
  
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;    Attempt to un-fuck Github Pages fuckery with Jekyll remote-theme;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;AGAIN
&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;  
    Remove theme gem from Gemfile
  
commit 5978bd4e828f72749e604e9fd8138ce27a322a32
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;Author: Divay Prakash &amp;lt;divayprakash0@gmail.com&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;Date:   Mon Feb 17 19:19:55 2020 +0530
  
    Attempt to un-fuck Github Pages fuckery
  
    Replace Ruby Gem method of theme installation with Github Pages method
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Anyhow, now I have the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;remote_theme&lt;/code&gt; solution implemented. And wouldn’t you know it, it’s still fucked! It becomes so bad that at this point it just randomly errors out -&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-console highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;Conversion error: Jekyll::Converters::Scss encountered an error while
                  converting 'assets/css/main.scss':
                  File to import not found or unreadable: so-simple.
                  Load path: C:/Ruby25-x64/lib/ruby/gems/2.5.0/gems/
                  jekyll-theme-primer-0.5.4/_sass on line 13
jekyll 3.8.5 | Error:  File to import not found or unreadable: so-simple.
Load path: C:/Ruby25-x64/lib/ruby/gems/2.5.0/gems/jekyll-theme-primer-0.5.4/_sass
on line 13
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;All this because for some reason the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;github-pages&lt;/code&gt; gem’s fallback theme is being used while &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;remote_theme&lt;/code&gt; is ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scouring StackOverflow, Jekyll forums, Github issues etc. gave me some possible solutions which I somehow patched together to get something working.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But then I switched networks from using mobile hotspot to a stable WiFi and lo-and-behold, now &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; fails randomly -&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-console highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;jekyll 3.8.5 | Error: Net::ReadTimeout
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I get that my Internet connectivity is to blame for this, but really? To top it all off, the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-remote-theme&lt;/code&gt; gem that enables all this functionality doesn’t support caching between command invocations, but only between builds (the feature is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/benbalter/jekyll-remote-theme/pull/56&quot;&gt;WIP&lt;/a&gt; for now). So every time something like a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; or a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll build&lt;/code&gt; runs, it downloads the theme again. Even when it works, it takes too long; over 40s to download a ~800kB zip file.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where does all this leave me?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Option 1 - Gem based theme
Works perfectly on local machine, doesn’t work on Github Pages&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Option 2 - &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;remote_theme&lt;/code&gt; using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;github-pages&lt;/code&gt; gem
Works on Github Pages, but flaky on local machine at the best of times&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where do I go from here?
    &lt;figure class=&quot;align-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/who-the-fuck-knows.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Divay Prakash</name><email>divayprakash0@gmail.com</email></author><category term="rant" /><category term="frustration" /><summary type="html">At the point I last posted, I was just getting into exploring a new Jekyll theme for my blog. Now, after having sunk just over 3 days into the endeavour I find myself here, in abject misery.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blogging like a hacker</title><link href="https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/16/blogging-like-a-hacker.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blogging like a hacker" /><published>2020-02-16T01:06:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-02-17T17:44:00+05:30</updated><id>https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/16/blogging-like-a-hacker</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://randommusings.netlify.com/blogging/code/2020/02/16/blogging-like-a-hacker.html">&lt;p&gt;Let me just start off by saying that this post is (heavily) inspired by (or, creatively plagiarized from) Tom Preston-Werner’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://tom.preston-werner.com/2008/11/17/blogging-like-a-hacker.html&quot;&gt;original&lt;/a&gt; from 2008.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with the disclaimer out of the way, let’s begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been toying with the idea of setting up a blog for over 5 years now, almost since the time I began my engineering studies. Right from my first exposure to coding and creating something of my own, I wanted to document my experiences, more so for myself than for anyone else, which is how my feelings towards a blog remain to this day. I agree I write in a conversational manner like I am addressing a reader, but that just makes it easy for me. And also, I do love writing. I enjoy putting my thoughts to paper, or the digital word here. It sometimes feels almost like a release, like there are so many thoughts running amok in my mind that it’s easier to just spew them all out in one single place rather that try and control the flow in any way, shape, or form. And that’s why I make so many typos when I’m composing a blog post, requiring me to use aggressive spell checks and even proof-reads to actually obtain something not resembling absolute garbage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as much as I enjoy this writing gig, I seem to be stuck in an endless loop of quitting and starting all over again. I do fancy myself to be somewhat of an aesthete, and having knowledge of programming and web development, I’m well equipped to tinker with the innards of technical solutions for blogging. Which is how it starts, I’d see a nice blog, good layout, interesting design, and off I’d go down the rabbit hole, exploring Wordpress, or Blogger, or Jekyll, or Hugo, or Ghost, or whatever else it was that managed to tickle my fancy. I’d keep at it for a few days but ultimately give up, convinced I didn’t have the necessary time to waste or some equally lame excuse. But this time, I kept at it with a firm resolve to introspect and really find what exactly led me into this destructive pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found was this - complication and/or over-simplification. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a feature set in mind when I set out to create a blog; attractive modern design, good typography, customization options - both in design and functionality, category and tag support, built-in SEO and overall ease of use. But it isn’t easy for me to find all of these things in any one stack or solution. My first blog adventure started with Blogger, but I quickly lost interest owing to the limited customization options and just general old-world feel. Next came Wordpress, which took way too long to setup the way I liked it and even then wasn’t a good solution at the best of times. Slow loading webpages, lack of content ownership, complex structure and technical stack; and all for a simple blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally settled on a static site using a generator such as Jekyll, or Hugo, or Ghost. However, this came with its own challenges, namely smaller developer communities and the possibility of running into issues that would be beyond me. Even choosing the most popular of the three, Jekyll, I had to contend with themes that did not fit my specific requirements even after some amount of effort on my part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with Rohan Chandra’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rohanchandra/type-theme&quot;&gt;Type Theme&lt;/a&gt;, I added tag and category support and made various visual changes to the blog format, ultimately giving it up in favour of John Otander’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/johno/pixyll&quot;&gt;Pixyll&lt;/a&gt;. This is where I am at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, even after all this exploration - wading through the murky waters of PHP, Apache, SQL, Ruby, Textile, Liquid, and god-knows-what else, I still am not 100% satisfied. Before I go any further, one clarification I have to make is that I am not trying to throw shade on the work of either Rohan or John’s projects, both of which helped me improve my skills in using Jekyll. Something is still holding me back and I find myself digging through the code much more often than actually writing out posts. Which made me realize that (I am a bit of a freak), I am a perfectionist, and I’ll not be pleased until something suits me perfectly (and the only till my definition of perfection changes!). So here I am, looking for a change again, exploring Michael Rose’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://mmistakes.github.io/so-simple-theme/&quot;&gt;So Simple Jekyll Theme&lt;/a&gt; at 1 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This moment of astounding clarity led me to type out this post, which I think is my longest till now (and by some margin). Just to record how totally and completely ass-backwards one can get sometimes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;align-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/here-we-go.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cheers to sleepless nights and endless explorations!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; : Just to clarify the title - blogging like a “hacker” :man_technologist: - The title is just a reference to the fact the through the journey of setting up my blog, I realised that whatever else I may be, a coder I definitely am! I wasn’t satisfied with the built solutions offered by Wordpress or Blogger, and just had to create something I could understand inside and out. And also, seamless updates with Ruby Gem-based themes rock :metal:!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Divay Prakash</name><email>divayprakash0@gmail.com</email></author><category term="exploration" /><summary type="html">Let me just start off by saying that this post is (heavily) inspired by (or, creatively plagiarized from) Tom Preston-Werner’s original from 2008.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Flying (not so) high</title><link href="https://randommusings.netlify.com/flying/2020/02/08/flying-not-so-high.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flying (not so) high" /><published>2020-02-08T11:21:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-02-08T11:21:00+05:30</updated><id>https://randommusings.netlify.com/flying/2020/02/08/flying-not-so-high</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://randommusings.netlify.com/flying/2020/02/08/flying-not-so-high.html">&lt;p&gt;As I said before, I type this now on my connecting flight, now on a Bombardier Q400NG Bash 8 bound for Dibrugarh. This really is one aircraft I love flying on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow (and I really don’t actually know how) it turns out that these are far more comfortable as compared to regular jet aircraft in India like the A320s or the B737s. There is loads more legroom, and the seats are more comfortable. The noise is noticeably more of course, but that’s to be expected with a propeller. However, some noise cancellation headphones sort that right out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plane also flies at a lower altitude all through the flight, meaning that you can see so much more! And on a clear day like today is, I can see clear till the ground, which feels really special. Even at cruising altitude, I am enjoying sceneic views from the comfort of my seat, sipping on a cappuccino.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, this may not seem like much, but lately I’ve found myself finding joy in the smallest of things. I did make a conscious effort to be more mindful of my surroundings, but I didn’t think I’d see results so early. Just goes to show the importance of enjoying the little things!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Divay Prakash</name><email>divayprakash0@gmail.com</email></author><category term="little things" /><summary type="html">As I said before, I type this now on my connecting flight, now on a Bombardier Q400NG Bash 8 bound for Dibrugarh. This really is one aircraft I love flying on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Flying High!</title><link href="https://randommusings.netlify.com/flying/2020/02/08/flying-high.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flying High!" /><published>2020-02-08T08:09:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-02-08T08:09:00+05:30</updated><id>https://randommusings.netlify.com/flying/2020/02/08/flying-high</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://randommusings.netlify.com/flying/2020/02/08/flying-high.html">&lt;p&gt;So, my first post. Here goes…….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing this while 30,000 feet in the air on board a Boeing 737-85R, travelling from Mumbai to Guwahati. I had to being that up because it’d give me an opportunity to talk about my love of flying. I never thought of pursuing it as a career option, and flying for fun was just out of the question for me. Yet there is something about flying that just captures my imagination like nothing else (well, with the exception of cars, but I’ll probably talk about it some time later so we can leave that for now). Anyhow, suffice it to say that I really enjoy flying. I’ve only travelled on narrowbodies for now, but I hope to change that soon. Come on the Indian government, keep Air India alive for 4 more months so I can catch a B747. The Queen is the widebody that I want to experience the first (no puns intended!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know whether it’s the sights, the sounds, or the technical and engineering marvel that amazes me the most. I’d say its a combination of all of those factors. However, I feel the most important thing is the freedom. Not freedom in the sense that an airplane gives you literal wings to travel anywhere, there’s no scope for that on commercial flights. No, what I mean is the freedom from the rest of the world. Develop a thick-enough skin that you can shrug off the person sitting next to you, and flying becomes an absolute joy. No one can reach you. No one can disturb you. It’s the time my imagination is as its most active, painting pictures in the sky and clouds. An endless string of emergencies can happen on the ground and I can be blissfully unaware of them. Don’t confuse this for my being a selfish a**hole, but sometimes I think it’s one of the simplest joys of 21st century life to just take a step back from it all. Switch off your phones, turn down the lights and give space to all the thoughts that run through your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But enough for now, I have a connecting flight to catch and the clouds are beckoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ciao!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Divay Prakash</name><email>divayprakash0@gmail.com</email></author><category term="clouds" /><summary type="html">So, my first post. Here goes…….</summary></entry></feed>